<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CytoData Society</title><link>http://cytodata.org/</link><description>Recent content on CytoData Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cytodata.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CytoData 2023 - by University of Helsinki and University of Turku</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2023/</guid><description>This year’s meeting will take place in Helsinki, Finland on October 23-26, 2023 hosted by the Institute for Molecular Medicine Finland (FIMM), the University of Helsinki and the University of Turku. The event will focus on Single-cell profiling and Spatial profiling, including a fantastic set of invited speakers, workshops, oral and poster presentations, and the popular hackathon. Check the program and submit your registration and abstract on the CytoData 2023 website.</description></item><item><title>CytoData 2022 - by Allen Institute for Cell Science</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2022/</guid><description>Cytodata 2022 will be hosted in-person by the Allen Institute for Cell Science in Seattle, WA on October 17-20, 2022. The Allen Institute for Cell Science is a division of the Allen Institute, whose mission is to create dynamic and multi-scale visual models of cell organization, dynamics and activities that capture experimental observation, theory and prediction to understand and predict cellular behavior in its normal, regenerative, and pathological contexts.
This year’s theme is “Data analysis and deep learning strategies for image-based profiling in cell biology.</description></item><item><title>CytoData 2021 - by bit.bio</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2021/</guid><description>CytoData Symposium 2021 will be hosted virtually by bit.bio from October 13-15, 2021. More information can found at the website.</description></item><item><title>CytoData 2020 - by Recursion Pharmaceuticals</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2020/</guid><description>Because of the COVID-19 pandemic, this year’s CytoData meeting will be held virtually. Attendees will join together over video conference for an exciting two-day symposium. Each session will be approximately two hours long.
https://www.rxrx.ai/cytodata2020</description></item><item><title>CytoData 2019 - by DKFZ</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2019/</guid><description>We are honored to host the fourth CytoData Symposium and Hackathon from Oct 28-30, 2019 at the DKFZ, Heidelberg, Germany! CytoData brings together the community of researchers mining microscopy image data.
https://2019.cytodata.org/</description></item><item><title>CytoData 2018 - by Broad Institute</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2018/</guid><description>We were honored to host the third CytoData Symposium and hackathon from Sep 21-25, 2018 at the Broad Institute, Cambridge, MA, USA! CytoData brings together the community of researchers mining microscopy image data.
https://2018.cytodata.org/</description></item><item><title>CytoData 2017 - by Institute of Cancer Research</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2017/</guid><description>Following the success of last years Cytomining Hackathon, where data scientists from 20 of the worlds top high-content screening laboratories came together to set a path for the field, the hackathon is back. Running over 3 days and 3 nights, we’ll begin with a day of talks, networking, and discussion before getting down to the hacking itself. For the Hackathon we’ll prepare a previously unseen imaging dataset. Working in groups, your task will be to develop novel software and analysis techniques to extract information from the dataset.</description></item><item><title>CytoData 2016 Hackaton - by Carpenter Lab</title><link>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/symposia/2016/</guid><description>Researchers mining image data are gaining momentum: papers are shifting from proof-of-principle to biological discovery. But we are not yet much of a true community, beyond reading each others’ papers and a few pairwise interactions at conferences. We would like to change this by bringing everyone together in the same room! Collectively, we have tremendous knowledge and insights into this challenging field.
https://2016.cytodata.org/</description></item><item><title>Juan Caicedo</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/juancaicedo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/juancaicedo/</guid><description> Responsibilities Contribute to shaping the society&amp;rsquo;s mission and initiatives. Mentor current president, document responsibilities and pass along to current president</description></item><item><title>Loan Vulliard</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/loanvulliard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/loanvulliard/</guid><description>Loan Vulliard is currently AIH Postdoctoral Fellow at the DKFZ in Heidelberg, Germany. He works together with Felix Hartmann and Julio Saez-Rodriguez to reveal the quantitative principles underlying molecular biology and to better understand human health and diseases. For this, he uses data analysis methods and collaborate with experimentalists and experts in the fields of immunology and cell biology. In particular, he is developing machine learning approaches to identify and contextualize spatial patterns in multiplexed ion beam imaging (MIBI) data.</description></item><item><title>Alexandr Kalinin</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/alexkalinin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/alexkalinin/</guid><description>Alex Kalinin is a Postdoctoral Associate in Machine learning for Computational Biology at the Imaging Plaform of the Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard, where he works with Shantanu Singh and Anne Carpenter. He is interested in developing and applying machine learning methods for studying cellular organization and improving disease diagnosis and treatment.
Responsibilities Design strategy for communications (frequency of announcements, venues for announcements, event announcements only, job listings, paper updates in the field, etc.</description></item><item><title>John Arevalo</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/johnarevalo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/johnarevalo/</guid><description>John Arevalo is a postdoctoral fellow at the Imaging Platform in the Broad Institute of Harvard and MIT. He works with Anne Carpenter and Shantanu Singh in the application of machine learning methods to uncovering causes and treatments for disease using heterogeneous biological data.
Responsibilities Contribute to shaping the society&amp;rsquo;s mission and initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Lassi Paavolainen</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/lassipaavolainen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/lassipaavolainen/</guid><description>I am a group leader at the Institute for Molecular Medicine Finland (FIMM). My research group focuses on developing and applying machine learning methods for image-based profiling of microscopy imaging data. We study deep learning methods to extract complex information from fluorescence microscopy images of human cell and tissue samples that are employed for instance in cancer precision medicine applications. I was the CytoData society president 2020-2021.
Responsibilities Organize the CytoData2023 event and keep documentation of CytoData events.</description></item><item><title>Paula A. Marin Zapata</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/paulaamarinzapata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/paulaamarinzapata/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a data scientist in the Machine Learning Research group at Bayer Pharma AG, focusing on deep learning applications to high content imaging. I have a background in biological engineering and applied mathematics.
Responsibilities Design strategy for communications (frequency of announcements, venues for announcements, event announcements only, job listings, paper updates in the field, etc.) Maintain mailing list Maintain society website Monitor contact email inbox</description></item><item><title>Gisele Miranda</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/giselemiranda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/giselemiranda/</guid><description>I am a researcher at KTH Royal Institute of Technology in Sweden. I am also an active member of the BioImage Informatics Facility at the Science for Life Laboratory, where I support researchers in developing computational methods for analyzing microscopic images. I have a keen interest in the intersection of computer science and biology, and I have been working on multidisciplinary research projects in the biomedical field involving computer vision, machine learning, and data analysis.</description></item></channel></rss>