<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Board on CytoData Society</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/</link><description>Recent content in Board on CytoData Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cytodata.org/board/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Juan Caicedo</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/juancaicedo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/juancaicedo/</guid><description> Responsibilities Contribute to shaping the society&amp;rsquo;s mission and initiatives. Mentor current president, document responsibilities and pass along to current president</description></item><item><title>Loan Vulliard</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/loanvulliard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/loanvulliard/</guid><description>Loan Vulliard is currently AIH Postdoctoral Fellow at the DKFZ in Heidelberg, Germany. He works together with Felix Hartmann and Julio Saez-Rodriguez to reveal the quantitative principles underlying molecular biology and to better understand human health and diseases. For this, he uses data analysis methods and collaborate with experimentalists and experts in the fields of immunology and cell biology. In particular, he is developing machine learning approaches to identify and contextualize spatial patterns in multiplexed ion beam imaging (MIBI) data.</description></item><item><title>Alexandr Kalinin</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/alexkalinin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/alexkalinin/</guid><description>Alex Kalinin is a Postdoctoral Associate in Machine learning for Computational Biology at the Imaging Plaform of the Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard, where he works with Shantanu Singh and Anne Carpenter. He is interested in developing and applying machine learning methods for studying cellular organization and improving disease diagnosis and treatment.
Responsibilities Design strategy for communications (frequency of announcements, venues for announcements, event announcements only, job listings, paper updates in the field, etc.</description></item><item><title>John Arevalo</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/johnarevalo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/johnarevalo/</guid><description>John Arevalo is a postdoctoral fellow at the Imaging Platform in the Broad Institute of Harvard and MIT. He works with Anne Carpenter and Shantanu Singh in the application of machine learning methods to uncovering causes and treatments for disease using heterogeneous biological data.
Responsibilities Contribute to shaping the society&amp;rsquo;s mission and initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Lassi Paavolainen</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/lassipaavolainen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/lassipaavolainen/</guid><description>I am a group leader at the Institute for Molecular Medicine Finland (FIMM). My research group focuses on developing and applying machine learning methods for image-based profiling of microscopy imaging data. We study deep learning methods to extract complex information from fluorescence microscopy images of human cell and tissue samples that are employed for instance in cancer precision medicine applications. I was the CytoData society president 2020-2021.
Responsibilities Organize the CytoData2023 event and keep documentation of CytoData events.</description></item><item><title>Paula A. Marin Zapata</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/paulaamarinzapata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/paulaamarinzapata/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a data scientist in the Machine Learning Research group at Bayer Pharma AG, focusing on deep learning applications to high content imaging. I have a background in biological engineering and applied mathematics.
Responsibilities Design strategy for communications (frequency of announcements, venues for announcements, event announcements only, job listings, paper updates in the field, etc.) Maintain mailing list Maintain society website Monitor contact email inbox</description></item><item><title>Gisele Miranda</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/giselemiranda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/giselemiranda/</guid><description>I am a researcher at KTH Royal Institute of Technology in Sweden. I am also an active member of the BioImage Informatics Facility at the Science for Life Laboratory, where I support researchers in developing computational methods for analyzing microscopic images. I have a keen interest in the intersection of computer science and biology, and I have been working on multidisciplinary research projects in the biomedical field involving computer vision, machine learning, and data analysis.</description></item><item><title>Ashley Anderson</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/ashleyanderson/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/ashleyanderson/</guid><description>Ashley Anderson is currently a software engineer at Chan Zuckerberg Initiative where he works to support biomedical image analysis and acquisition. Ashley holds a Ph.D. in Medical Physics from the University of Wisconsin - Madison, and previously worked on software and magnetic resonance imaging R&amp;amp;D for Barrow Neurological Institute, Philips, and Hyperfine, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Louise Morlot</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/louisemorlot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/louisemorlot/</guid><description>I am a PhD student at the University of Copenhagen, at the Center for Protein Research in Niels Mailand laboratory. I work on genomic instability and DNA damage mechanisms; for this I develop and use deep learning models and multi-omics approaches.
Responsibilities Contribute to shaping the society&amp;rsquo;s mission and initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Ziqi Kang</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/ziqikang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/ziqikang/</guid><description>I am a doctoral student at the University of Helsinki, focusing on profiling the tumor microenvironment and discovering spatial-related immune response mechanisms from multiplexed images. I am developing unbiased automatic computational tools to deeply quantify spatial information.
Responsibilities Contribute to shaping the society&amp;rsquo;s mission and initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Erik Serrano</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/erikserrano/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/erikserrano/</guid><description>I am a PhD student at the University of Colorado, AnschutzMedical Campus (CU-AMC). I work in Gregory Way&amp;rsquo;s Lab, where my research involves developing software for reproducible cell morphology data analysis workflows.
Responsibilities Contributing to CytoData and the community.</description></item></channel></rss>