<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Board on CytoData Society</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/</link><description>Recent content in Board on CytoData Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://cytodata.org/board/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lassi Paavolainen</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/lassipaavolainen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/lassipaavolainen/</guid><description>I am a senior scientist working at the Institute for Molecular Medicine Finland (FIMM). My research focuses on representation learning from microscopy images applied to cancer research. My background is in computer science, bioimage informatics and software engineering.
Responsibilities Mentor current president, document responsibilities and pass along to current president</description></item><item><title>John Arevalo</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/johnarevalo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/johnarevalo/</guid><description>John Arevalo is a postdoctoral fellow at the Imaging Platform in the Broad Institute of Harvard and MIT. He works with Anne Carpenter and Shantanu Singh in the application of machine learning methods to uncovering causes and treatments for disease using heterogeneous biological data.
Responsibilities Contribute to shaping the society&amp;rsquo;s mission and initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Juan Caicedo</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/juancaicedo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/juancaicedo/</guid><description> Responsibilities Lead the committee, keeping the society’s vision and strategy in mind Automatically becomes Past president after two years of service</description></item><item><title>Paula A. Marin Zapata</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/paulaamarinzapata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/paulaamarinzapata/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a data scientist in the Machine Learning Research group at Bayer Pharma AG, focusing on deep learning applications to high content imaging. I have a background in biological engineering and applied mathematics.
Responsibilities Design strategy for communications (frequency of announcements, venues for announcements, event announcements only, job listings, paper updates in the field, etc.) Maintain mailing list Maintain society website Monitor contact email inbox</description></item><item><title>Loan Vulliard</title><link>http://cytodata.org/board/loanvulliard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://cytodata.org/board/loanvulliard/</guid><description>Loan Vulliard is currently AIH Postdoctoral Fellow at the DKFZ in Heidelberg, Germany. He works together with Felix Hartmann and Julio Saez-Rodriguez to reveal the quantitative principles underlying molecular biology and to better understand human health and diseases. For this, he uses data analysis methods and collaborate with experimentalists and experts in the fields of immunology and cell biology. In particular, he is developing machine learning approaches to identify and contextualize spatial patterns in multiplexed ion beam imaging (MIBI) data.</description></item></channel></rss>